Muhammad Rizwan S/O Muhammad Aslam Arif

Mail ADDRESS:

Home No. 255-Jade Block, Park View Villas. Main Multan Road, Lahore.

CONTACTS:

0092-332-6768495 Rizwanaslam1986@gmail.com Rizwanaslam1986@hotmail.com

EDUCATION:

1) GC University, Faisalabad

M.SC Industrial Chemistry (2007-2010)

- Literature and Practical survey on Industrial
 Utilization of Water and treatment Methods
- Internship Bioethanol production by molasses
- Thesis on the Proximate Analysis and Mineral Composition of Sugar Industry Byproducts (Molasses, Bagasse and Press Mud).

2) AIOU, Islamabad

B.Ed. Science (2011-2013)

3) IQRA University, Karachi

MBA Marketing (Continue)

TRAININGS, CERTIFICATES &

WORKSHOPS:

- 1 day training workshop on "Management Skills "by Sitara Chemicals and Lyallpur Fertilizer, Jaranwala, Faisalabad.
- 5 days training workshop on "Production and quality management Skills" by Pakistan Steel Mills and People Steel Mills, Karachi Pakistan.
- 1 day training workshop on "Communication and Analytical Skills "by GC University, Faisalabad and Karachi University, Karachi Pakistan
- Excellent performance certificate as "Trainee Industrial chemist" from Shakarganj Mills Ltd, Jhang
- "Good Organizer" in IEEE Tech Fair Certificate of Recognition in GC University, Faisalabad.
- "ISO 9001-2008 Coordinator" production department at Auriga Group, Lahore
- 1 day training certificate on "Communication Skills" by HRD Auriga Group, Lahore
- 1 day training certificate on "Teams & team work" by HRD Auriga Group, Lahore
- 2 days training certificate on "ISO 18001-2007 Occupational safety& health series" by CIWCE Punjab, Pakistan
- 2 days Training on "Respiratory Protection in working field" by CIWCEPunjab, Pakistan

Professional Summary:

An experienced & skilled professional in business development, operation & team management in different business sectors with product development and market relate prospects. To ensure effective & efficient coordination with teams for uplift the business growth and competitive visibility.

EXPERIENCE

1) Deputy Manager Production & Quality Assurance Auriga Group of companies, Lahore, Pakistan June, 2010 – February, 2016

Job Expertise & Skills:

- Planning, scheduling & checking management system regarding marketing and customer demand to deliver products/consignment timely.
- Supporting marketing & operations teams regarding product quality matters and follow up the customer's demands/Problems.
- Meeting with the clients and make them understand the changes for different compliances as a marketing consultant.
- Coordinating with regional and global teams for execution of regional plans for savings, sourcing and innovation.
- Analyzing failure, corrective and preventive action to respond to customer complaints.
- Responsible for planning, organizing and managing the overall activities of receiving / outgoing quality functions.
- Feedback of quality problems from marketing teams /customers and find solutions to improve quality levels with quality assurance team.
- Ensure the effective and efficient operation of team to provide quality improvement leadership for valued customer & consumers.
- Attend all required targets, goals & trainings as assigned from team leader/manager.
- Produce training materials and curriculum for quality concerns to support new customers, consumers& marketing staff.
- Report quality scores of product and urgency situation to the customer, consumer and other stakeholders.
- Provide reports on product quality status to marketing staff, customer, consumers & managers on demand.
- Drive continuous improvement activities (product services, production planning, supply chain Process, facilities, materials,).
- Notify line problems to the Quality Control staff and improve the quality level.
- Build and maintain good working relationships with Team Members and management.
- Support the Quality Inspectors to ensure that products and processes comply with the relevant requirements of the quality management systems.
- Dedication and meeting the project goals under target schedule.
- Management and Leadership Skills can handle large scale and small scale projects.
- Take pride in hard work, Quick learner& Team player
- MS Office (word, excel, power Point & outlook), data merging and documentation.

2) Executive Supply Chain (Commercial Fuels Q.A-Business Development) Attock Petroleum Ltd. Sheikhupur, Pakistan March, 2016 – December, 2017

Job Expertise & Skills:

• Coordinate with operation and marketing teams for smooth business growth with different quality and operation concern matters.

STRENGTHS & SKILLS

- Planning & Sourcing
- forecasting
- Team management
- Marketing development
- Operation Management
- Monitoring & evaluation
- Decision making
- Research & strategy
- Procurement
- Clients dealing
- Customer services
- Sales development
- Interpersonal
- Communication
- Negation
- Reporting
- Emphasizing Excellence
- Conflict Resolution
- Objection Handling
- Product Knowledge
- Time Management
- Client Relationships
- Energy Level
- Meetings Management
- Presentation Skills
- Production Planning
- Task Management
- Microsoft Office

FUNCTIONAL AREAS:

- Business Development
- Training and contents
- Industrial Production
- Marketing & sales
- Monitoring & Evaluation
- Operations & Production
- Planning & Execution
- Product Development
- Public Relations
- Quality Assurance (QA)
- Project Management
- Supply Chain
- Chemicals

HOBBIES:

- Research articles
- Book Reading
- Marketing trends
- Teaching
- Travelling
- Contacting

- Assure the quality checks of commercial fuels according to ASTM Methods for retails and corporate quality compliances.
- Maintain the desire levels of product quality in daily services through pipe line operation and TL'S.
- Build test studies and create technical script for marketing development and also for corporate clients.
- Work to improve organization's efficiency and profitability by quality management system.
- Analyze and report the work with subject to QMS documentation.
- Make daily, weekly, quarterly and annual reports of operation work.
- Maintain daily log books of instruments calibration checks.

3) Executive Lubricants

(Operations & Product Development) Attock Petroleum Ltd. Karachi, Pakistan January, 2018 – December, 2018

Job Expertise & Skills:

- Successfully manage & monitor the product formulation, process, operation and all its criteria's as per market demand.
- Successfully achieved plans and the project scheduled goals.
- Successfully coordinate with operation team as per schedule and achieved marketing development goals.
- Reviewed constantly the consumer feedback and suggest ways to improve the processes and customer service satisfaction levels at best peak.
- Ensured the successfully procurement of raw materials and packing materials with best quality levels as per marketing demands.
- Ensured to achieve the monthly and annually targets timely by implementation the new loyalty programs for clients.

4) Executive Corporate Sales

(Urban pest Development - IPM/IPC/IRS Projects) ECO Pest Solution, Evyol Group February, 2019 -- Continue

- Maintain relationships with clients by providing support, information, and guidance urban pest developments and launch IPM project.
- Research and recommend new opportunities and methods to uplift profit and service improvements.
- Meet the corporate client for more business option in urban pest developments.
- Research business opportunities and indentify new prospects.
- Ability to understand and respond the client's / customer needs or demands.
- Sell products by establishing contact and developing relationships with prospects.
- Understanding marketing techniques, sale cycle and recommending solutions.
- Prepare reports by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing information of clients Maintains quality service.

Teaching Experience:

- 1) S.T Chemistry, Hi-Tech Public School, Faisalabad. (09/2007-08/2008).
- 2) S.T Chemistry, Fairy Land High school, Faisalabad. (10/2008-02/2010)
- 3) Lecturer Chemistry, Igra academy, Karachi. (05/2018-12/2018)

Reference:

Will Available on request.